(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-17T23:17:13.587622",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
今日も大天才！大天才！
Today, I'm a super genius! Super genius!
あ〜ずっともっと推し事させてっ
Ah~ Let me keep fan-girling forever and ever!
今日はリリカの生誕祭ライブ！見に来てくれてありがとう！
Today is Ririka's birthday live! Thank you for coming to watch!
たくさんのゲストとコラボいっぱい歌うからね！
I'll be singing lots of collaborations with many guests!
盛り上がっていこう！
Let's get excited and hype it up!
アクスタ 痛バ ぬい 準備万端！
Acrylic stand, ita-bag, plushie—all set!
オシャレも気合い入れちゃってさ
Dressed up and full of enthusiasm,
『誰の為なの〜？』
"Who is it for~?"
企むことなき推しの為です！
It's for my beloved faves, with no hidden agenda!
古参 新参も人権は平等
Old fans, new fans, everyone has equal rights,
内に秘めた古参マウント
Though there's a hidden flex of being an OG fan...
Not 同担拒否ですが
I'm not against sharing my fave,
すごーし嫉妬はするかも…！
but I might get a tiny bit jealous...!
「いいね！」ボタン足りません…
One "Like" button isn't enough...
これ無料でいいんですか…？
Is it really okay for this to be free...?
尊すぎるでしょ
It's way too precious, right?
困っちゃうなあ
Oh, what am I to do~
今日も大天才！大天才！
Today, I'm a super genius! Super genius!
推しなし無理 絶対 考えたくもないなあ
Life without my fave is impossible, I don't even wanna think about it!
推し事は年中無休です
Supporting my fave is a year-round job with no days off!
もう大天才！
Truly a super genius!
あー限界 これ以上供給されたら困ります
Ah, I'm at my limit! Any more content and I won't be able to handle it!
だって召されたら
Because if I pass away from bliss,
免罪！免罪！あなたがイチバン！
Not guilty! Not guilty! You're the absolute best!
予約した推しのフィギュア
The figure of my fave that I pre-ordered...
来年発送予定！？ (マジ！？)
...is scheduled to ship next year?! (Seriously?!)
そんなの慣れっこです
But I'm totally used to that!
忘れた頃にくるけど…！
Though it arrives right when I've forgotten about it...!
溢れる祭壇 無限回収ですが
My shrine is overflowing from endless collecting,
せるふかーどのままに増えすぎる らびゅー！
but it keeps growing on my credit card, love you!
あ～もう好き！
Ah, I just love you so much!
今日も大天才！
Super genius again today!
大天才！死ぬ！無理！待って！
Super genius! I'm dying! Too much! Wait!
てぇてぇ！考えられないや…
So wholesome! I can't even process this...
尊死！
Dying from preciousness!
次の現場まで待てないや
I can't wait until the next live event!
もう大天才！
Truly a super genius!
あー限界 切り詰めた生活
Ah, I'm at my limit! Living on a tight budget...
なにひとつ苦じゃないだって
...isn't painful at all, because...
こんなにも幸せ溢れた日々です！
...my days are overflowing with so much happiness!
来年も再来年も
Next year, the year after next,
その先ずっと何年でも
and for all the years beyond that,
推していたい 好きでいたい
I want to keep supporting you, keep loving you!
でもあなたの幸せが イチバン！
But your happiness is what matters most!
無理だけはしないでね？
Just please don't overexert yourself, okay?
あなたとあなたを見つけ出した
Thank you to you, and to myself...
私に“ありがとう”を
...for finding you!
今日も大天才！ だーいてんさいっ！
Super genius again today! A true super genius!
なんてそんなに大天才？ 困るよ
Why are you such a super genius? It's overwhelming!
完璧すぎるじゃん もう大天才！
You're just too perfect! Truly a super genius!
だーいてんさいっ！
A true super genius!
推しの死 無理絶対 考えたくもないなぁ♪
Life without my fave? Absolutely impossible, I don't even wanna think about it!
生き甲斐！
My reason to live!
推し物は年中無休です
Supporting my fave is a year-round job!
もう大天才！
Truly a super genius!
あぁ～限界 これ以上供給されたら困ります
Ah, I'm at my limit! Any more content and I won't be able to handle it!
だって召されたら
Because if I pass away from bliss,
免罪！免罪！あなたがイチバン！
Not guilty! Not guilty! You're the absolute best!
推しに勝るものは無し！
Nothing beats my fave!
われらの恋の始まりは
The beginning of our love story...
触れた瞬間 アララララ
...was the moment we touched, oh my my my!
あーこれは困った 二度と元に戻らない
Ah, this is a real problem, we can never go back!
そして星が生まれまして
And then a star was born!
明け方の一番星は
The first star at dawn...
あなたと出会った
...was meeting you!
これは次元を揺るがす大発見
This is a dimension-shaking major discovery!
このままハート打ち上げて どこまでも高い空へ
Launching our hearts high into the sky like this, to the end of the sky!
メッチャ飛んじゃいたい
I wanna fly so high!
スタースタースタートしたこのラブは
This love that went "Star Star Start"...
あなたがいなきゃ今頃超新星
...would have gone supernova without you!
するぞっ (オー！オー！) しちゃうぞ！？ (オー！オー！)
I'll do it! (Oh! Oh!) I really will! (Oh! Oh!)
あなたに言ってるんだっ！
I'm talking to you!
スタスタスタンドあの追ってる
Standing, standing, standing, chasing that...
ほら目の前にずっとある一等星
...first-magnitude star that's always right before my eyes!
みてる (オー！オー！) きいてる (オー！オー！)
Looking at it! (Oh! Oh!) Listening to it! (Oh! Oh!)
このビッグバン気づいて！
Notice this Big Bang!
ナナナナナナナナ
Na-na-na-na-na-na-na-na!
愛は地球くらいに膨らんでこんなになってんぞ
My love expanded to the size of Earth and became like this!
ナナナナナナナナ
Na-na-na-na-na-na-na-na!
捜査対象は興奮の本命のスター！
The subject of my search is the thrilling, genuine star!
電電電波送信 あなたのハートにノーティス
Sending radio waves, notice in your heart!
暇つぶしでいいよみたいな顔して
Looking like "just to kill time is fine"...
ちょっとの反応くれたの喜ばしい
...I'm delighted by even the slightest response from you!
てかこんなの逃すなんて嘆かわしい
Honestly, missing out on this would be deplorable!
われらの星の活動は 割と続いてモホホモハ
Our star's activities have continued quite a bit, mohohomoha!
いやーこれはすごいな つまりあなたと私の創世記
Wow, this is incredible, meaning our genesis...
このままハートあなたごと連れてかなたを目指すだろう
...will take your heart along with you, aiming for the far beyond!
メッチャ飛んじゃった
We flew so high!
スタースタースタートしたこのラブは
This love that went "Star Star Start"...
あなたがいなきゃ今頃超新星してた
...would have gone supernova by now without you!
してたかー！ (オー！オー！)
Did it?! (Oh! Oh!)
ほら今日まで続いた！
Look, it's continued all the way until today!
スタースタースタートちゃんとわかってね！
"Star Star Start," make sure you understand it well!
いっそ高度増して輝く一等星！
A first-magnitude star shining even higher!
あなたと！
With you!
わたしで！
And me!
ビッグバン級の...
Big Bang-class...
愛は
Love is...
愛は地球くらいに膨らんでこんなになってんぞ
Love expands to the size of the Earth, becoming like this!
育ててきた声は
The voices we've nurtured...
このときのために
Are for this very moment...
スタート！
Start!
DINDON DINDON 鼓動がビディビディ
DINDON DINDON, my heart goes bidi-bidi
期待も急上昇 感じて
Expectations surging, feel it!
JOY JOY もっと ENJOY ピッカピカのSTREAMING
JOY JOY, ENJOY more! Sparkling STREAMING
上々気分持ってるぜ ホームラン
Feeling super great, hit a home run!
ラッキー押しの一手 才脳 ひらめきはワン
Relying on luck and talent, an inspiration in one!
見せてあげる ラブリーパーティ
I'll show you a lovely party!
チルるんチルるん巻き起こる これまた台風
Chill-run chill-run, kicking up another typhoon!
もっとHAPPY トコトントコトン届けちゃうよ
Sending you even more HAPPY, down to the very end!
そうだろ？こうだろ？ときめきたろー？
Right? Like this? Isn't it exciting?
ラララウィズユー いかがでしょうか？
La la la with you, how is it?
ちょっとビビッと感じたら
If you feel a little spark...
止められない 留まらないくらい胸のドッキドキ！
My heart pounds so much I can't stop or hold it back!
一周回って現在進行形 ぐるぐる追いかけっこ
Going full circle in the present progressive, playing chase!
あららら アラモード
A-la-la-la, A la mode!
このまま行くよ
Here we go just like this!
DINDON DINDON 鼓動がビディビディ
DINDON DINDON, my heart goes bidi-bidi
期待も急上昇 もっと感じて
Expectations surging, feel it even more!
JUMPING JUMPING DISPLAY お邪魔します！
JUMPING JUMPING DISPLAY, pardon me!
ご気分新設定
Setting a fresh new mood!
大体色とりどりは認めません
Generally, color variation is not allowed!
史上最高の一言まいどー！
The best line ever, thanks as always!
YOU & I ここからREADY
YOU & I, READY from here!
ずっと見ててね
Keep watching me always!
リリカルモンスターズ☆
Lyrical Monsters!
DINDON
バズるかな？ 勢いをBOOM BOOM
Will it go viral? Momentum BOOM BOOM!
もっと騒げ ぶちかませ BOOM BOOM
Make more noise, blast it BOOM BOOM!
ドカン！だけじゃない ノットンノッていこう！
Not just a BANG! Let's get into the groove!
褒めて 伸びて 有頂天
Praise me, grow, over the moon!
アゲアゲ アゲアゲ テンパれば脳内台風
Up and up, up and up, panic and a typhoon in the brain!
やっぱクレイジー ビシバシビシバシ決めちゃうよ
Super crazy after all, nailing it crisp and sharp!
キミをLOVE キミをLOVE ギブユーラブガーデン
Love you, love you, give you love garden!
おかわり いかがでしょうか？
How about a second helping?
もっとメイメイと感じてよ
Feel it more clearly and distinctly!
やめられない 目が離せない キミのハッシュタグ
Can't stop, can't take my eyes off your hashtag!
ハック！
Hack!
もう一回回って通常運転 のびのびいつも通り
One more turn, back to normal operation, carefree as usual!
あららら あらかると
A-la-la-la, A la carte!
このまま行くよ
Here we go just like this!
DINDON DINDON 予測不能
DINDON DINDON, unpredictable!
想像以上のショータイム
A showtime beyond imagination!
スルーするから BUMPING BUMPING
Ignoring it, so BUMPING BUMPING!
開いた口が塞がらない 発言も大歓迎
A jaw-dropping speech is also most welcome!
孤独なんかじゃありません
You are not alone!
空前絶後の言葉マジシャン
Unprecedented word magician!
YES ALL YES 何でもALL RIGHT
YES ALL YES, everything is ALL RIGHT!
一緒に新感覚
Together, a new sensation!
リリカルモンスターメージ
Lyrical Monster Mage!
本当はね、リリカちゃんと2人で歌って踊ってみたかったって思ってたんだけどね
To tell you the truth, I always wanted to sing and dance together with Ririka-chan,
まさかこんな形で叶うなんて！
and I never thought it would come true like this!
誰が一番驚いてるって、団長だよねー！
The one who's most surprised is Dancho herself!
人は誰しも悩む時もあるよ
Everyone has times when they worry,
そこが良いところ
and that's what makes it good!
どんな日も笑顔にする魔法
A magic that brings a smile to any day!
どんどん笑って
Laugh more and more!
表情筋ニコニコ 100万ボルト
Facial muscles smiling with 1 million volts!
あららら LOVE & PEACE
A-la-la-la, LOVE & PEACE!
このまま行くよ
Here we go just like this!
まだまだ行くよ
Going even further!
ついてきてよねー！
Follow along, okay?
DINDON DINDON みんななら
DINDON DINDON, if it's all of you,
DINDON DINDON できるはずさ
DINDON DINDON, you should be able to do it!
DINDON DINDON 聞かせて
DINDON DINDON, let me hear it!
DINDON 大きな声で
DINDON, in a loud voice!
DINDON DINDON 鼓動がビディビディ
DINDON DINDON, my heart goes bidi-bidi!
期待も急上昇 もっと感じて
Expectations surging, feel it even more!
JUMPING JUMPING DISPLAY お邪魔します！
JUMPING JUMPING DISPLAY, pardon me!
ウルトラハッピーでサロン
Ultra happy salon!
大体色とりどりは認めません
Generally, color variation is not allowed!
史上最高のノリノリの柄だから
Because it's the most high-energy pattern ever!
バツグンバツグンLOVE
Outstanding, outstanding LOVE!
一緒に新感覚
Together, a new sensation!
リリカルモンスターメージ
Lyrical Monster Mage!
リリカルモンスター☆シャッフル！イェーイ！
Lyrical Monster Shuffle! Yeah!
DINDON
膝跪きなさい！
Kneel before me!
汝 この城の扉を叩いた者よ
Thou who hast knocked upon the gates of this castle...
誓いなさい
Make your vow!
このルーナの盾となり 矛となり
Become the shield and spear for this Luna...
夜はぐっすり眠れるまで
Until you can sleep soundly at night...
共にあることを！
Promise to stay by my side!
捧げなさい 姫であると
Offer your devotion, to your princess!
ルーナって 紅茶のカップをガチャガチャ鳴らさないで偉い！
Luna is so great for not clinking her teacup loudly!
スコーンだってこぼさずに綺麗に食べてすごい！
It's amazing how you eat scones neatly without spilling crumbs!
たまに王冠どっちが前か間違っちゃうの可愛い！
It's cute how you sometimes forget which way the crown goes!
だってよしなのなら 快調！
If that pleases your Highness, all is well!
ルーナイト第一条！
RooKnight Article 1!
何よりルーナが好きな人！
Those who love Luna above all else!
ルーナイト第二条！
RooKnight Article 2!
シロップの蓋開けてきて！
Open the syrup lid for her!
ルーナイト第三条！
RooKnight Article 3!
3時のお茶会来れる人！
Those who can attend 3 o'clock tea!
守れなかったら即制裁！
Immediate punishment if unkept!
分かってほしいのなら
If you want me to understand...
これも帝王学を学ぶため
This is also to learn the art of emperorship...
愛という名の教育なのらー！
It's education in the name of love!
守ってルーナイト 思ってルーナイト プロムナード ボイコット なのなのら
Protect me RooKnight, care for me RooKnight, promenade boycott nano nanora!
手の甲にチュッ 嘴唇にチュッ ガラスの靴履かせてワルツ
Kiss the back of my hand, kiss my lips, put on glass slippers and waltz!
守ってルーナイト 留まってルーナイト 愚民にキャンディーどれだけあってもね
Protect me RooKnight, stay RooKnight, no matter how many candies the subjects have...
君がいなきゃだってミュート
Without you, everything is muted!
誇らしくて捧げなさい 姫であると
Proudly offer your devotion, to your princess!
ルーナってお菓子のおあとちゃんと歯磨きするのエライ！
Luna is so great for brushing her teeth after sweets!
目覚まし無くたって起きられちゃうのすごい！
It's amazing how you can wake up without an alarm!
ステップこんがらかっちゃったのも可愛い！
Even getting your dance steps tangled up is cute!
今日はお褒めの言葉よしなのなら 快調！
If today's praise pleases your Highness, all is well!
ルーナイト第四条！
RooKnight Article 4!
ルーナを本気にさせる人！
Those who make Luna get serious!
ルーナイト第五条！
RooKnight Article 5!
ダイヤの花束摘んできて！
Pluck a bouquet of diamonds for her!
ルーナイト第六条！
RooKnight Article 6!
ドラゴンペットにできる人！
Those who can make a dragon their pet!
つべこべ言わずに即実行！
Do it immediately without talking back!
きっと分かってくれるのなら
If you will surely understand...
講習論だって読んだのら
I even read treaties on public discourse!
恋はいつだって試練なのらー！
Love is always a trial!
守ってルーナイト 踊ってルーナイト オペラハウス貸切なのなのら
Protect me RooKnight, dance with me RooKnight, reserving the entire opera house!
プロ入手にチュッ 誓約書にチュッ ドレスの薔薇咲かせてワルツ
Kiss the pro contract, kiss the pledge, bloom roses on the dress and waltz!
守ってルーナイト 分かってルーナイト バラードに粉ミルクにシュガーのせちゃう
Protect me RooKnight, understand me RooKnight, adding powdered milk and sugar to the ballad!
あの子も綺麗だってそうなの？
Is that girl pretty too? Is that so?
戯言はおやめなさい 姫であると
Cease your nonsense, for I am your princess!
守ってルーナイト 思ってルーナイト プロムナード ボイコット なのなのら
Protect me RooKnight, care for me RooKnight, promenade boycott nano nanora!
永遠のチュッ この指にチュッ ガラスの靴履かせてワルツ
An everlasting kiss, a kiss on this finger, put on glass slippers and waltz!
守ってルーナイト 困ってルーナイト 愚民にキャンディーどれだけあってもね
Protect me RooKnight, be troubled RooKnight, no matter how many candies the subjects have...
君がいなきゃだってミュート
Without you, everything is muted!
誇らしくて捧げなさい 姫であると
Proudly offer your devotion, to your princess!
なのうし おりゃまし 突っ込み無用で 本日改定
No objections or comebacks allowed, rules revised today!
さわろ ぽろ ぎゅむ ばき 手にするすべて イッツマイ くれくれ
Touch, drop, squeeze, snap! Everything in reach is "It's mine, gimme gimme!"
適当に頑張ろ
Let's just do our best casually...
そんなくらいでいいけどさ
That much is fine and all, but...
必死に頑張ろ
Let's work hard with all our might!
それが僕らしいよな
Yeah, that feels more like us!
ダサすぎじゃねぇんだわ
It's not uncool at all!
そんで貧ぼっちじゃねぇんだわ
And we're not lonely or broke either!
うん！ 万事バッチリイケてるに決まってる！
Yep! Everything is definitely going great!
あーゆうかなたちゃん どどんと言い切っちゃって
That Amane Kanata-chan, declaring it so boldly!
ちゃんと歓迎して
Welcome her properly!
どこまでも行こう 想像ちゃんと超えだして
Let's go anywhere, going beyond all expectations!
そうしよう
Let's do that!
僕が言うんだもん
'Cause I'm the one saying it!
本当にするんだもん
I'm really gonna do it!
現実超える未来
A future beyond reality...
弱点もヘキ スイッチ入れなくっちゃ
Weaknesses and quirks, gotta flip the switch!
(ワンダラーダー)
(Wanderader!)
すなわち特者生存ワンダラーダーDAY
In other words, "Survival of the Unique" Wanderader DAY!
(ワンダラーダー)
(Wanderader!)
楽しもう 面白がれること探して参上
Let's enjoy, arriving in search of fun things!
返事聞かせてくれ
Let me hear your response!
右左のどっちじゃない
It's neither right nor left,
(ワンダラーダー)
(Wanderader!)
決めつけて一触即発
jumping to conclusions, a hair-trigger situation!
(ワンダラーダー)
(Wanderader!)
ちなみになくのなら発車
By the way, if you're crying, we're departing!
ライダー ワクワクするぜ ライダー
Rider! Getting excited, Rider!
聞いて！ 推しができた！ 逢いに行くの楽しい！ でもガチの欠航は立ち直れてません！
Listen! I got a fave! Going to meet them is fun! But I still haven't recovered from the actual flight cancellation!
だから出るまで回すの100%ピックアップ！
So I'm gonna spin until I get it, 100% pick-up!
天井です！
Hit pity!
なんだよそんなこと言っちゃダメだおバカ！
What's that? You shouldn't say that, dummy!
賢い！ ありがとう！
That's smart! Thank you!
日々これ挑戦 で我のマイウェイ
Every day is a challenge, that's my way!
こうしたいんだーって言いたいんだもん だって息ガンガンが良いんだもん
'Cause I wanna say "This is what I want!" 'Cause living life at full throttle is best!
全方位にガッツリ アンテナ張っていなくっちゃ
Gotta keep my antennas raised in all directions!
いつでも心はちゃんと純粋で
My heart is always purely genuine,
(ワンダラーダー)
(Wanderader!)
一代の好奇心は絶えず熱心で
A lifetime of curiosity is constantly enthusiastic,
(ワンダラーダー)
(Wanderader!)
一体になって
Becoming as one!
いい気になってんの？ 調子に乗ったらすぐ飽きられちゃうから
Are you getting carried away? 'Cause if you get cocky, people will get tired of you real fast!
あー 最高だろ 応答せよ
Ah, isn't it the best? Please respond!
(ワンダラーダー)
(Wanderader!)
すなわち特者生存ワンダラーダーDAY
In other words, "Survival of the Unique" Wanderader DAY!
(ワンダラーダー)
(Wanderader!)
勝機見つけ
Find a chance to win!
努力とは最後まで諦めないこと
Effort means not giving up until the very end!
メモっておいて！
Take a note of that!
本当はbaby 自信なんかないよ
Honestly, baby, I have no confidence at all,
本当はbaby 不安ばっかで泣きそうだ
Honestly, baby, I'm full of anxiety and feel like crying.
でもねbaby くじけないって決めたの
But you know, baby, I decided not to give up.
だからbaby 挑戦したいよ 未開の地で 未知のフィールドで
So baby, I want to take on the challenge in an unexplored land, an unknown field!
ギター！
Guitar!
前進せよ ちゃんと覚悟して
Press forward, fully prepared!
(ワンダラーダー)
(Wanderader!)
たくましく行こう 想像ちゃんと共鳴して
Let's go strongly, resonating with our imagination!
(ワンダラーダー)
(Wanderader!)
興奮しよう！
Let's get excited!
僕が言うんだもん
'Cause I'm saying it!
本当にするんだもん
'Cause I'm really gonna do it!
現実超える未来
A future beyond reality...
弱点もヘキ スイッチ入れなくっちゃ
Weaknesses and quirks, gotta flip the switch!
(ワンダラーダー)
(Wanderader!)
すなわち特者生存ワンダラーダーDAY
In other words, "Survival of the Unique" Wanderader DAY!
(ワンダラーダー)
(Wanderader!)
楽しもう 面白がれること探しい放題せ
Let's enjoy, search for fun things to your heart's content!
無限のフィールドで
In an infinite field!
パニックになったってもいい
It's fine even if you panic,
(かなたー)
(Kanata-!)
どまんなかいっちゃって
go straight through the middle!
(かなたー)
(Kanata-!)
ちなみにこれが僕の答えなんだ
By the way, this is my answer!
胸をはれ 今を生きるその意味を 明ける日も暮れる日も確かめ進め
Hold your head high, day in and day out, confirm the meaning of living now and press on!
あー！ ありがとうございましたー！
Ah! Thank you so much!
ありがとう！ ありがとう！
Thank you! Thank you!
はい、というわけで皆さん、一条莉々華生誕祭ライブ2025にお越しくださりありがとうございます！
All right, so everyone, thank you so much for coming to Ichijo Rika's Birthday Live 2025!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
今日なんと、もう一人ね、祝ってもらってるの呼びたいと思います！ かなた先輩！
Today, I'd like to call out someone else who's here to celebrate with us! Kanata-senpai!
イェーイ！
Yay!
莉々華ちゃんお誕生日おめでとう！
Ririka-chan, happy birthday!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
莉々華真ん中おいで。 ありがとうございます！
Ririka, come to the middle. - Thank you so much!
やった！ めっちゃ嬉しいです！ 来てくれてありがとうございます！
Yay! I'm so happy! Thank you for coming!
早速、自己紹介させていただいてもよろしいですか？ もちろんですよ！
May I go ahead and introduce myself? - Of course!
やった！ 本日の主役！ 可愛いポジティブジーニアスの一条莉々華だよー！ イェーイ！
Yay! The star of today! The cute, positive genius, Ichijo Rika! Yay!
大人になりました。
I've become an adult.
いやー、なんかセクシーさに磨きがかかったんじゃないのー？
Wow, hasn't your sexiness been refined even further?
むちむちです！ むちむちです！
I'm voluptuous! Voluptuous!
大人を狙っている。
Aiming for maturity.
やった！ 先輩たちも自己紹介をお願いします！
Yay! Senpais, please introduce yourselves as well!
はーい！ ヘイ！ こんかなたー！ キャッチコピーは握力50キロ！ ギュッギュッ！ 握りつぶしちゃうぞー！ ホロライブ4期生、かなたんこと天音かなたでーす！
Okay! Hey, Kon-Kanata! My catchphrase is "50kg grip strength! Squeeze, squeeze! I'll crush you!" From Hololive Generation 4, I'm Amane Kanata, also known as Kanatan!
可愛いー！
Cute!
ギュッギュッ！
Squeeze, squeeze!
はーい！ みんな、こんこよー！ ホロライブの頭脳！ 天才頭脳研究員！ 博衣こよりだよー！
Okay! Everyone, Kon-Koyo! The brain of Hololive! The genius researcher, Hakui Koyori!
わあー！ ジーニアスが奪われるー！
Wah! My "genius" title is being stolen!
すみません！ 誕生日なのに奪っちゃって！
Sorry! Stealing it away even though it's your birthday!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
なんか変な動きしてた、恥ずかしい
I was making weird movements, how embarrassing!
おもろいから大丈夫！
It was funny, so it's fine!
両方にいるからね！両方見たい...
She's on both sides! I want to look at both...
ありがとう、ありがとう
Thank you, thank you!
改めまして、生配信ライブスタートしたわけなんですが
Once again, our live stream has officially started...
今回の配信のハッシュタグ！
The hashtag for today's stream!
右上にあるこちら！
It's right up here on the top right!
ハッシュタグ #一条莉々華生誕祭2025 となってます！
The hashtag is #IchijoRikaBirthdayFest2025!
Xでたくさんポストしてくれると嬉しいです！
I'd be so happy if you post a lot on X!
スクショとか感想とか、もりもり待ってます！
We're eagerly waiting for your screenshots and thoughts!
もりもり待ってるからね！
We're really waiting!
まずかなた先輩と「特者生存ワンダラダー！」を歌わせていただきました！
First, we sang "Tokusha Seizon Wonder-Lader!" with Kanata-senpai!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!
この曲本当にかわいくて！
This song is really so cute!
踊りもめっちゃかわいいし！
The dance is super cute too!
嬉しい！ありがとう！
I'm so happy! Thank you!
めちゃくちゃ歌えて踊れて嬉しかったです！
I was so happy to sing and dance to it!
莉々華のソロでね、踊ってもらえて本当に幸せでした！
I was so happy to dance it for Rika's solo live!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
そしてこの後ね！こよちゃん先輩とは...
And up next! With Koyo-chan-senpai...
あの曲を！
That song!
莉々華の大好きな曲で！
It's a song that Rika loves so much!
ええー！本当に？！
Ehhh, really?!
ん？ちょっとおかしいよ！
Hm? Something's weird!
なんだこれ？！赤くなってる！
What is this?! It turned red!
これ大丈夫か？
Is this okay?
なんか出てくる！ゾンビだー！
Something's coming out! It's zombies!
きゃあああ！
Kyaaaa!
莉々華！行け！
Rika! Go!
きゃあああ！
Kyaaaa!
ちょっと！どうなってるのこれー！
Hey! What's going on with this?!
嘘でしょ？！
No way!
待ってください！あそこに...
Wait! Over there...
ゾンビ撃退クリームがある！
There's Zombie Repellent Ice Cream!
ソフトクリームでしょ！
Isn't that just soft serve ice cream?!
違います！これは幻のクリームですよ！
No! This is the legendary cream!
説明役の顔して言ってちゃダメだよ！
You can't just say that with an explainer's face!
これをゾンビに当てれば...
If we hit the zombies with this...
多分ゾンビを消滅できるはず！
Maybe we can eliminate the zombies!
やばいやばい！行け行け！
Oh no oh no! Go go!
見てろ！物理なんだ！
Watch this! It's physical?!
ああー！痛い！
Ahhh! Ow!
生きてる！やばいやばい！
They're still alive! Oh no oh no!
莉々華ー！
Rikaaa!
ふう...お！なんとか成敗しました！
Phew... Oh! We managed to defeat them!
あぶないあぶない！一瞬乗っ取られそうだったけどな！
That was close! For a second it almost took over!
乗っ取りは完了ということで...
The takeover is complete...
乗っ取られてんの？ゾンビに？
Wait, it WAS taken over?! By zombies?!
大丈夫です！あ！戻った！
It's okay! Ah! It came back!
戻ってきたー！よかったー！
It's back! Thank goodness!
一体何だったんだよ、莉々華ー！
What on earth was that, Rika?!
いや、実はですね...お化け屋敷感みたいなのを、せっかく遊園地だから味わってほしいなって思って...
Well, actually... since we're in an amusement park, I wanted you to experience a haunted house feel...
ええー？！ジェットコースターがよかったー！
Ehhh?! I wanted a roller coaster!
スモークは焚いてほしいって言ったんですけど...
I did ask them to set off some smoke, though...
まさかゾンビまで出てくるとは思わなくて...
I didn't think zombies would actually show up...
怖すぎるだろ！説明がおかしかったぞ！
That's way too scary! Your explanation was so weird!
最初はちゃんと対応してたのにな！
You handled it so properly at first, though!
と！いうことでですね！
So! With that being said!
この後はこよちゃん先輩と...歌わせて...
Up next, with Koyo-chan-senpai... we'll sing...
この状態で？！どういう心境で歌えばいいんだ...
In this state?! What mindset are we supposed to sing with?...
かなた先輩、この後もここでまったりゆっくりしててくださいなー！
Kanata-senpai, please relax and take it easy here after this!
こっちで楽しんでるね！
Okay! I'll enjoy myself over here!
私たちは...行ってきます！
We're... off!
嘘でしょ...え、ひとりぼっち？
No way... Eh, all alone?
僕ひとりぼっちにさせられてんだが...
I've been left all by myself...
もう君いなくたって上手くやっちゃえ
I'll do just fine even without you!
WAO!!
こよちゃん先輩！来てくれてありがとうございます！
Koyo-chan-senpai! Thank you so much for coming!
絶対無理思っちゃうし　だって　だって　不安になるし
I think it's impossible, 'cause, 'cause I get anxious,
全然嘘つけないし　だって　だって　わがまますぎるし
I can't lie at all, 'cause, 'cause I'm way too selfish,
目指すキラキラの切符は僕次第だ
The sparkling ticket I aim for depends on me!
ギブアップなんて言わないんだから
I'm not gonna say I give up!
じっとしてらんないし　だって　だって　動いちゃう足
I can't stay still, 'cause, 'cause my feet keep moving,
ワン・ツー・ステップ　ちょっとずつ進めば　夢の仕掛け解けちゃうな
One-two step, taking it step by step, solving the tricks of my dreams!
なりたい僕を　君が好きな僕を　ちゃんとあまりなく見せてたいな
The me I want to be, the me you like, I want to show you without holding back!
あっちゃっちゃー　びっくりするほどできないじゃん　間違って悩んでばかりじゃん
Oh dear, I'm shockingly bad at this, making mistakes and worrying all the time!
みつけてほしくて
Wanting you to find me,
僕は君を迎えに行くんだ
I'm coming to meet you.
出会えたなら HAPPY
If we can meet, it's HAPPY!
WAO!! WAO!! おた叫んじゃえ
WAO!! WAO!! Let's shout out loud!
泣いて 泣いて 愛して 尾っぽ振って
Cry, cry, show love, wag your tail!
WAO!! WAO!! おた叫んじゃえ
WAO!! WAO!! Let's shout out loud!
ダメな僕を どうか覚えておいて
Please remember a helpless me like this.
もう君の心 ちくっとしちゃえ
Let me prick right into your heart!
もうどうしようとかたまに思っちゃって沈んだり
Sometimes I wonder what to do and feel down,
あんがい行けるかも ふわりジャンジャッてまたダウン!?
"Maybe I can do it?" bouncing up, only to fall down again!?
ベッタリがやめられない お座りってそれなんだっけ?
I can't stop clinging to you; what does "sit" even mean?
うっかりが止められない またルンルンでぶつかるの
I can't stop being clumsy, happily bumping into things again!
ワンワンステップアップ 死んだふりしてるの?
Woof woof, stepping up! Are you playing dead?
やめてはいこっちおいで!
Stop that, come over here!
欲しがる君と あげすぎな僕とで
With a needy you and an over-giving me,
もっといける気がしています
I feel like we can go even further!
あっ
Ah!
びっくりするほどできないじゃん
I really can't do this at all, can I?
間違って悩んだりばっかりじゃん
Just making mistakes and worrying all the time.
手をつなごう
Let me hold your hand!
みつけてほしくて
Wanting you to find me,
僕は君を迎えに行くんだ
I'm coming to meet you.
出会えたなら HAPPY
If we can meet, it's HAPPY!
だって やっぱりひとりじゃダメだけど
Because being alone is no good after all,
集まってバカして騒いっちゃえば
but if we gather, fool around, and make noise,
ほらいつでも言える「おかえり」
see, we can always say "Welcome back!"
僕は君に伝えたいんだ
I want to tell you this...
大いなる HAPPY
A giant HAPPY!
WAO!! WAO!! おた叫んじゃえ
WAO!! WAO!! Let's shout out loud!
泣いて 泣いて 愛して 尾っぽ振って
Cry, cry, show love, wag your tail!
WAO!! WAO!! おた叫んじゃえ
WAO!! WAO!! Let's shout out loud!
ダメな僕を どうか覚えておいて
Please remember a helpless me like this.
目指すキラキラの切符 僕次第だ
The ticket to the sparkling stage depends on me!
妥協なんて言わないで
Don't talk about compromise!
メラメラでぶっちぎれ!
Burn brightly and dash past everyone!
シナシナでハグレずに希望へダイブ!
Don't wither away or stray, dive straight into hope!
君の心 ちくっとしちゃっていいじゃん HAPPYちゃん
Let me prick into your heart, it's fine, HAPPY-chan!
常世の闇に 囚われたまま 奏でる悲鳴を
Trapped in everlasting darkness, let me hear the screams you play...
聴かせて
...let me hear them.
さあ 爪を磨いたら まだ子供のようなあなたのために
Now, once I polish my nails, for your sake, who is still like a child...
あぁ 試されたいなら その愚かな手に手錠をかけて
Ah, if you want to be tested, put handcuffs on those foolish hands.
常世の闇に 囚われたまま 甘い甘いガムを噛んでいた
Trapped in everlasting darkness, chewing sweet, sweet gum...
いくつもの後悔を 捧げて
Offsetting countlessly many regrets...
さり気ない合図に隠れた 答えはすぐにわからせてあげる
Hidden behind a casual signal, I'll make you realize the answer right away.
微小な嘘にまみれた 拒んだままに受け止めてあげる
Smeared with subtle lies, I'll embrace you even as you refuse.
ほら 悲鳴を 聴かせて
Come on, let me hear your screams.
さあ 指を鳴らしたら この子猫のようなわたしのために
Now, when I snap my fingers, for my sake, who is like a kitten...
あぁ 喉が乾いたわ 口紅の口に指を散らして
Ah, my throat is dry; brush your fingers over my lipstick-stained lips.
狭い牢獄に閉じ込めたまま 首輪に繋がれてたいの
Locked away in a narrow prison, wanting to be chained by a collar.
くだらないルールじゃ 奪えない 自由は既にこの手の中にある
Unsnatchable by silly rules, freedom is already within these hands.
愛想では 測れない 弱ったままに選ばせてあげる
Unmeasurable by mere flattery, I'll let you choose even while weakened.
ほら 心を開いて
Come on, open your heart.
分からないフリをして 眠けているの？
Pretending not to understand, are you feeling sleepy?
もっと熱い暗闇を見せて ねぇ
Show me a hotter darkness, hey...
さり気ない合図に隠れた 答えはすぐにわからせてあげる
Hidden behind a casual signal, I'll make you realize the answer right away.
微小な嘘にまみれた 拒んだままに受け止めてあげる
Smeared with subtle lies, I'll embrace you even as you refuse.
常世の闇に 刻む名を
The name carved into everlasting darkness...
わからせてあげる ほら 悲鳴を 聴かせてよ
I'll make you realize it. Come on, let me hear your screams!
夢見ないで
Don't dream...
ほら 聴かせて
Come on, let me hear it.
四六時中 乖離の階で 面倒くさを押し付けられてる 何から何まで
24/7 on this level of divergence, I'm stuck with all the hassle, every single thing.
仕事はやめて まとめ役なら 聞くのを上手に 頷き合ってる 仲良しこよしで
Stop working; if you're the coordinator, agree politely, nodding along like good old friends.
さあ だんだんだんだん 黙れ黙りたまえよ
Now then, shh, shh, quiet down, just hold your tongue!
言わないで そんな強い言葉は 少しだけ静かにしてほしいな
Don't use such harsh words; I just want a little peace and quiet...
ああ 私たち大亡霊
Ah, we are great phantoms.
伏伏伏く やいやいやい 果たすその日まで
Prostrate, prostrate, prostrate, yeah, yeah, yeah, until the day it's done!
煉煉煉獄 いえいえいえ あなたの周りも よよよ
Purgatory, purgatory, purgatory, yeah, yeah, yeah, all around you too!
潜潜潜伏 あれあれあれ 約束の地まで
Lurking, lurking, lurking, oh, oh, oh, until the promised land!
さあ 掲げよ バッテンバッテン 伏伏伏く やいやいやい
Now raise an X, cross cross! Prostrate, prostrate, yeah, yeah, yeah!
今日も議題ソッチノケだね 嫌になるから 私ひとりでもやっておきますね
Today's agenda is pushed aside again; since it's annoying, I'll just handle it myself.
すべて すべて すべて任せて それをさせてよ 大事なことなの 分かっているでしょう
Entrust it all, all, all to me! Let me do it—it's important, you understand, right?
四六時中 乖離の階で 面倒くさいまま 今日も明日もすぎてゆくのでしょう
24/7 on this level of divergence, as tiresome as ever, today and tomorrow will pass us by.
花瓶に水をあげましょう 時のなか 萎れたこと忘れてた
Let's put water in the vase; I had forgotten it withered in time.
さあ だんだんだんだん 黙れ黙りたまえよ
Now then, shh, shh, quiet down, just hold your tongue!
言わないで そんな強い言葉は 少しだけ静かにしてほしいな ああ
Don't use such harsh words; I just want a little peace and quiet... Ah.
私達大亡霊
We are great phantoms.
今と未来 見たかったはずなのに
Even though we were supposed to see the present and future...
伏伏伏く やいやいやい 見えぬその日まで
Prostrate, prostrate, prostrate, yeah, yeah, yeah, until the unseen day!
然然然然 いえいえいえ この世の理を よよよ
Naturally, naturally, yeah, yeah, yeah, the laws of this world!
今は 潜潜潜伏 さあさあさあ あなたの街中 形作るオーバード
For now, lurking, lurking, lurking, come on! Shaping your town: Aubade.
伏伏伏く やいやいやい 果たすその日まで
Prostrate, prostrate, prostrate, yeah, yeah, yeah, until the day it's done!
煉煉煉獄 いえいえいえ あなたの周りも よよよ
Purgatory, purgatory, purgatory, yeah, yeah, yeah, all around you too!
潜潜潜伏 あれあれあれ 約束の地まで
Lurking, lurking, lurking, oh, oh, oh, until the promised land!
さあ 掲げよ バッテンバッテン 服服服したら 瓶詰めのワインをあけましょう
Now raise an X, cross cross! Once we submit, let's open a bottle of wine.
わーい！やったー！
Yay! Woohoo!
はい！ということで引き続きゲストパートをお送りしておりましたが！
All right! So we've been bringing you our guest segment, but...
なんと！もう一人MCに呼びたいと思います！
We'd actually like to call out one more person to join as MC!
誰だ誰だ誰だ〜？
Who could it be~?
トワ先輩ー！
Towa-senpai!
はい！はい！はい！イエーイ！
Yeah! Yeah! Yeah! Yay!
来てくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming!
いや、こちらこそー！
Oh no, the pleasure is all mine!
ちょっとせっかくなんで自己紹介していただいてもいいですか？
Since you're here, could you introduce yourself?
はい！オッケー！ホロライブ4期生の…あれ？
Sure! Okay! I'm Hololive 4th Gen... Wait, huh?
う…常闇トワでーす！
Uh... Tokoyami Towa here!
あれ？今「こんやっぴー」が無いから言えないんだ！
Wait, you couldn't say it because you didn't have a "Konyappi" call-in?
こんやっぴー！
Konyappi!
はい、皆さんまったりかねー！HoloXの女幹部、鷹嶺ルイと申します！
Hello everyone, keep it chill! I'm Takane Lui, executive officer of HoloX!
リリカ、お誕生日おめでとうー！
Ririka, happy birthday!
ありがとうございます！めっちゃ嬉しいー！
Thank you so much! I'm so happy!
喜びの舞！
A dance of joy!
いやー、呼んでくれて嬉しいよ、お誕生日にさ！
I'm really happy you invited me on your birthday!
ありがとうございます！もうルイ姉もトワ先輩も、もうすごいリリカに優しくしてくれる…
Thank you! Lui-nee and Towa-senpai are both always so nice to me...
リリカ的には姉御的な存在なので…
To me, you're both like big sister figures...
おー！まあまあまあ！
Oh! Now, now, now!
あんま謙虚じゃないね！
You're not being very humble, are you!
お前もトワのこと知ったれ！
You tell Towa about that too!
だから、めっちゃ嬉しいです！
That's why I'm super happy!
やばい、このキラキラについていけない！
Oh man, I can't keep up with all this sparkle!
などの遊園地なんです！
An amusement park...
えー！
Whoa!
めっちゃいい！ / ね！
That's so great! / Yeah!
最高のお...ですね。
It's the best stage...
ジェットコースターもあるんだよ。
There's even a roller coaster.
後で乗ろうよ。
Let's ride it later.
結構すごいスピードだよ。
It goes really fast.
ちゃんと乗れるようになっているんで、ぜひ乗ってもらいたいです！
It's fully rideable, so please give it a try!
じゃあ後で一緒に乗ろうよ。
Then let's ride it together later.
乗りたい！乗りたい！
I want to! I want to ride!
でも一旦実は出店も用意してるので、良かったら...
But actually, we also have food stalls set up over here, so if you'd like...
そう、こっちに来てください！
Yeah, please come this way!
こっちかな？
This way?
こっちです！こっちこっち！
Over here! Over here!
はーい！
Okay!
おー！ / じゃん！出店もありますよー！
Awesome! / Ta-da! We have food stalls, too!
すごーい！
So cool!
ポツンって今映ってる。
It looks so isolated right now.
ポツンじゃないだろ！ / バルーンもついてるんだから！
It's not isolated! / It even has balloons attached!
そうだね！ / そうですね！
That's true! / Indeed!
ちょっとこの出店でソフトクリーム食べれるんで...
You can get soft-serve ice cream from this stall...
Rikaが先輩達に、いつもお世話になってる先輩達にご馳走します！
Rika is going to treat the seniors who always look after her!
やったー！
Yay!
奢りですか？ / もちろんです！
Is it your treat? / Of course!
さすが社長だよ。
As expected of our CEO.
食べましょう、食べましょう！
Let's eat, let's eat!
大きくなりましたね！
You've grown so big!
じゃあ、いただきまーす！
Okay, let me get them for you!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
うわー、すごい！美味そう！
Wow, awesome! Looks delicious!
もらったー！良かったら食べてください！
Here you go! Please enjoy!
いただきまーす！
Thanks for the food!
ありがとう。美味いわ！ / 美味しい！
Thank you. It's so good! / Delicious!
サンキュー！甘ーい！
Thank you! So sweet!
ねぇ、めちゃくちゃ濃厚で美味いな。
Hey, it's super rich and delicious.
うん、いいソフトクリーム。
Yeah, good soft-serve.
普段アイス食べる？ / 食べる。
Do you usually eat ice cream? / I do.
食べる。アイス大好き。
I eat it. I love ice cream.
大好きですか？良かった！
You love it? Glad to hear!
私ミルクが好きなんよ。ミルクが... / ミルク美味いよね。
I like milk flavor... / Milk flavor is tasty, right?
うん。え、ルイねえは？
Yeah. What about you, Lui-nee?
え、私もね、このワッフルコーン大好きで。
Well, I really love waffle cones too.
よく食べるよ。
I eat them often.
ワッフルコーンいいよね。高級感あるわ。
Waffle cones are great. They feel premium.
それはそう！
That's so true!
Rikaはね、実はあんまりアイス食べないんですけど...
Actually, Rika doesn't eat ice cream much, but...
食べないんだ！
You don't?!
でも、氷が好き。
But I like shaved ice/ice flakes.
氷ね。クリーム系だけど今日ね。
Ice, huh? Though today it's creamy soft-serve.
そう！
Yeah!
しょうがないじゃん！クリームしかなかったんだもん！
I couldn't help it! They only had cream soft-serve!
いやいや、めちゃくちゃ美味いです。ありがとうございます。
No, no, it's super delicious. Thank you so much.
ということで、じゃあちょっと今回のライブステージも紹介させてください！
Anyway, let me introduce our live stage for this time!
お願いしまーす！
Please do!
じゃじゃーん！今回はなんと、遊園地ステージとなっております！
Ta-da! This time, it's an amusement park stage!
すごーい！
Amazing!
ロマンチック！
So romantic!
ねぇ、夜だからすごい綺麗だし、しかも凄くない？
Since it's night, it looks so pretty. Plus, isn't it awesome?
あ、ジェットコースターが今登って...
Ah, the roller coaster is going up right now...
うよー！
Whoa!
すげー乗りたい。
I really wanna ride it.
むっちゃ速い！ / マジ速い。
It's super fast! / Seriously fast.
時々遠くに見えるかもしれません、もしかしたら。
You might see it in the distance sometimes, maybe.
乗ってるの？！みたいな感じでね。
Like, "Wait, are they on it?!" kind of thing.
色々乗れるののがあるので、良かったら先輩達この後もまったりしていってください。
There are various rides you can take, so please relax and enjoy yourselves afterwards too, seniors.
え、いいんですか？ / うん！
Wait, is that okay? / Yep!
じゃあ2人で乗ってね。 / 乗って。
Then let's ride together, the two of us. / Let's ride.
ライブ見てるよ、こうやって手を振りながら。
We'll watch the live performance while waving like this.
映ったらごめんね。 / 見えるかもしれないどこかに。
Sorry if we show up on screen. / You might be visible somewhere.
ねぇ、もう本当に今日お2人に来ていただいてめちゃくちゃ嬉しくて...
Gosh, I'm genuinely so happy that both of you came today...
まず1個目が、Rikaね、トワ先輩の『FACT』を一緒に...
First off, Rika got to perform Towa-senpai's "FACT" together...
歌わせていただいたんですけど...
with her...
デビューした直後にReGLOSSで同時視聴、トワ先輩のライブを同時視聴させていただいて...
Right after debuting, we watched Towa-senpai's live stream together in ReGLOSS...
そうだよね、そうだよね。
That's right, that's right.
その時にこう『FACT』を聴いて、「やべぇ、めちゃくちゃカッコいい！」って...
And when I heard "FACT" back then, I was like, "Woah, that's so cool!"
Rikaもこんな風に歌えるようになりたい、踊れるようになりたいって...
I thought, "I want to be able to sing and dance like that too!"
そんな興奮してくれたの？ / マジでコレ！
You were that hyped about it? / Seriously!
だから今回こうやって一緒に歌って踊ってもらえて、本当に嬉しいです！
So to be able to sing and dance together with you like this, I'm truly happy!
こちらこそ、一緒にできて嬉しかったよ。ありがとうね。 / ありがとうございます！
Same here, I was happy to do it with you. Thank you. / Thank you so much!
ステキだった。
It was wonderful.
ルイねえとはね、『Overdrive』を歌って踊らせていただきました！
And with Lui-nee, we sang and danced to "Overdrive"!
いやぁ、めちゃくちゃ嬉し。
Gosh, I'm super happy.
『Overdrive』もめちゃくちゃ好きな曲で...
I love "Overdrive" so much as well...
言っといてくれてたもんね。 / そうなんです！「一緒に歌いたいな、いつか」って...
You used to mention that to me. / Yes! I kept saying, "I want to sing it with her someday"...
言ってたのが今回こうやって夢が叶って、もうめちゃくちゃ嬉しいです！
And now that dream came true today, I'm so over the moon!
嬉しい！めちゃくちゃカッコよかった、ダンスも歌も。
I'm so glad! You were incredibly cool, both the dancing and singing.
大人の色気、ちゃんと出せてましたか？
Did I manage to convey adult charm properly?
出せてましたよ！大人の色気。 / やっほー！嬉しい！
You definitely did! That adult charm. / Yay! I'm so glad!
素晴らしかったです。
It was marvelous.
やっぱり大人の色気ね、見せていきましたから。いかがだったでしょうか？
After all, we showed off that mature allure. How did you like it, everyone?
いかがだったでしょうか？！
How did you like it?!
なんでちょっと照れてるんですか？
Why are you acting a bit shy about it?
いやぁ嬉しい、本当にありがとうございました！ / ありがとうございました！
Aww, I'm so happy. Thank you both so very much! / Thank you very much!
まだRika、この後もあるので...
Rika still has more coming up after this, so...
お2人から「頑張れ」のエールを貰いたいです！
I'd love to get a "Do your best!" cheer from the two of you!
ソフトクリームももらったし、2人でね、お礼のね。
We got soft-serve ice cream, so the two of us should give a cheer as thanks.
せーの、で言うね。せーの...
We'll say it on "ready, set". Ready, set...
頑張れー！
Do your best!
あれ？どっか行った？
Huh? Where did she go?
Rikaー！
Rikaー!
Go go my way もう放っといて
止められない ness 任せて
Go go my way, just leave me alone
Unstoppable-ness, leave it to me
ゴリゴリな Rule は Break It Down
我慢できない Now I'm free
Break down those rigid rules
Can't hold back, now I'm free
目が眩んでしまいそうな出で立ちの...
Dressed up in an outfit so dazzling it blinds...
ロマメイド 憧れてた
I used to yearn for the romantic maid style,
だけど今は
But right now,
何も響かない
Nothing speaks to me anymore.
I know who I am
ブランディングには勘弁
Spare me from the branding,
今は完全無視
Right now I'm completely ignoring it.
なんてありの Greedy style
Living with my own greedy style,
ダサい髪も興味ないの
I don't care about uncool hair,
ありのままでいたい
I just want to stay true to myself.
Going going my way もうほっといて
Going going my way, just leave me alone.
止められない 熱気任せて
You can't stop me, surrender to the heat!
ゴリゴリのルールは Break It Down
Break down all those rigid rules!
我慢できない Let me free
I can't hold back, let me free!
We are special でしょ 揺るがない Price
We are special, an unshakable price.
それだけでいいの
That's all that matters.
たらればだらけの 呪いな日々を Break It Down Break It
Break down these cursed days full of "what-ifs"!
We are special でしょ 誰に言われても
We are special, no matter what anyone says,
私は歌うよ
I will keep singing!
アンフェアばかりの世界だけど Break It Down Break It 進め
It's a world full of unfairness, but break it down and forge ahead!
Break It Down Break It 進め
Break it down, keep pushing forward!
I just don't care about you
ハイテクなメイクやファッション
High-tech makeup and fashion,
Self-love には勝てないよ
Can't beat self-love.
この身と心 誰のものでもないでしょ
This body and soul belong to no one else, right?
いい加減大人だよ
Grow up already!
意味なき圧迫
Meaningless pressure,
あだになりだす Perfect
Perfectionism backfiring,
自分への成り代わり
Trying to become someone else.
でも今は楽しいよ ありのままでいられるから
But it's fun now, because I can be myself.
Going going my way もうほっといて
Going going my way, just leave me alone.
止められない 熱気任せて
You can't stop me, surrender to the heat!
ゴリゴリのルールは Break It Down
Break down all those rigid rules!
我慢できない Let me free
I can't hold back, let me free!
We are special でしょ 揺るがない Price
We are special, an unshakable price.
それだけでいいの
That's all that matters.
たらればだらけの 呪いな日々を Break It Down Break It
Break down these cursed days full of "what-ifs"!
We are special でしょ 誰に言われても
We are special, no matter what anyone says,
私は歌うよ
I will keep singing!
アンフェアばかりの世界だけど Break It Down Break It 進め
It's a world full of unfairness, but break it down and forge ahead!
Can't break me down, breaking me
Break It Down Break It Down
Break It Down Break It 進め
Break it down, keep pushing forward!
Break It Down Break It Down
Going going my way もうほっといて 止められない 熱気任せて
Going going my way, just leave me alone! Surrender to the heat!
ゴリゴリのルールは Break It Down 我慢できない Let me free
Break down all those rigid rules! I can't hold back, let me free!
続いての曲は、SUPER DUPER!
Next up is SUPER DUPER!
みんな準備いい？
Is everyone ready?
諦めない体で向かっていってね！
Face forward with an unyielding body and go for it!
Yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah oh oh
めくるめく好奇心は森羅万象
Dazzling curiosity spans all creation,
行く末神さえも知らぬ場所
Heading to places even gods do not know.
混じり気のない情熱が
Pure, unadulterated passion,
澄まして苦境を逆手にとる
Calmly turns adversity to our advantage.
寝付きの悪い夜も
Even sleepless nights,
途方のない現実も 目まぐるしい時代も全部
Helpless reality, and dizzying times—all of it!
忘却の彼方へ笑い飛ばそう
Let's laugh it off into oblivion!
Gimme the Gimme the Beep right now!
SUPER DUPER 王道駆けるの シャングリラ
SUPER DUPER, running down the royal road to Shangri-La!
日暮れるまで踊ろうよ
Let's dance until nightfall!
誰が何と言おうと 気にしないみたい
No matter what anyone says, we don't seem to care.
勝者だけのチームだけ 美しい声を響かせて
Only a team of winners, making beautiful voices resound!
Yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah oh oh
うつむいた世界を変えてみせよう
Let's change this downcast world!
今更躊躇してどうする 逆転
Why hesitate now? A sudden turnaround!
一発で決める 劇的作変
Deciding it in one shot with a dramatic turn of events!
転生してももう一度ここに Come back
Even if reincarnated, come back here once again.
人生そのものがセンセーショナルな漫画
Life itself is a sensational manga!
Beginnerから一夜 羽ばたいた Original
From a beginner overnight, taking flight as an original!
一番目指し走り出す天才 Genius
Aiming for number one, running forth like a genius!
巷を揺るがす Boy or Girl
Shaking up the streets, boy or girl!
憂鬱すら取っ払って 問題ない
Stripping away even gloom, no problem at all!
迫り付く憂鬱を愛してやまないもの
Those who endlessly love the approaching gloom,
歌が何も知らないまま
While the song remains unaware...
そう言っておける覚悟は出来てるよ
I'm fully prepared to say as much!
Gimme the Gimme the Beep right now!
SUPER DUPER 王道駆けるの シャングリラ
SUPER DUPER, running down the royal road to Shangri-La!
日暮れるまで踊ろうよ
Let's dance until nightfall!
誰が何と言おうと 気にしないみたい
No matter what anyone says, we don't seem to care.
高い城
High castle,
底無しのシームだけ
only a bottomless seam,
美しい声を響かせて
echoing a beautiful voice.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, ah, ah
俯いた世界を変えてみせよう
I'll show you I can change this downcast world.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, Super Duper!
生き自由も
Even the freedom to live,
一期一会注いで
pouring in each once-in-a-lifetime encounter,
一心同体を抱いて
embracing being two bodies, one mind.
容赦なく恋したメロディと 会えなくて手放した恋歌
With a melody I fell ruthlessly in love with, and love songs I let go without meeting,
間もなく君との境界線を越え リプレイ
soon crossing the border with you, replay.
Super Duper 無重力のシャングリラ 惹き付けられるまで踊ろうよ
Super Duper zero-gravity Shangri-La, let's dance until we're drawn together.
誰が何と言おうと 気にしないリミット
No matter what anyone says, a limit we don't care about.
高い城
High castle,
底無しのシームだけ
only a bottomless seam,
美しい声を響かせて
echoing a beautiful voice.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, ah, ah
俯いた世界を変えてみせよう
I'll show you I can change this downcast world.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, Super Duper!
というわけで！
And with that!
ReGLOSSでSUPER DUPERをお送りしました！
That was ReGLOSS performing SUPER DUPER!
みんな来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you everyone for coming!
さっきもやったんだけど、もう1回やってみてもいい？
We did it earlier, but can we try doing it once more?
いいよ！いつでもできます！
Sure! We can do it anytime!
リスタート？ We are ReGLOSS!
Restart? We are ReGLOSS!
せっかくだからちょっとみんなに自己紹介してほしくて。じゃあ奏から！
Since we're here, introduce yourselves. Starting with Kanade!
はい！えっと、一条莉々華の恋人、音乃瀬奏です！
Yes! Um, I'm Ichijou Ririka's lover, Otonose Kanade!
いつの間に恋人だったんだー！
Wait, since when were you lovers?!
莉々華、大好きだよー！
Ririka, I love you!
やったー！
Yay!
一条莉々華にゃの...
I'm Ichijou Ririka-nya's...
ぺチョー！
Pecho!
わんわんわん！
Woof woof woof!
違う違う違う！
No no no!
一条莉々華ちゃんの配信デスクの上のタンブラーを置くコースターみたいなやつ、儒烏風亭らデンです！
I'm Juufuutei Raden, the coaster thing under the tumbler on Ririka's desk!
何それ一体？！
What on earth is that?!
ずっと一緒やん！そういうことか！
That means you're always together! Ah, I see!
やったー！
Yay!
みんな来てくれて本当にありがとうねー！
Thank you all so much for coming!
楽しかったー！
That was so fun!
誕生日だっけ？何だっけ？
Was it a birthday? What was it?
違う、確認確認！
Wait, let's check!
そうです！莉々華、大人になりました！
That's right! Ririka has become an adult!
お誕生日おめでとうー！
Happy Birthday!
なんか誕生日っていいな。毎日誕生日がいい！
Birthdays are great. I wish every day was a birthday!
毎日歳取ることになるけど！
You'd age every single day though!
じゃあこの話は終わりということで！
Then let's end that topic!
置いといてね！
Setting that aside!
はい、じゃあここからはね、ちょっと告知をさせていただきたいなと思っております！
Alright, so from here on, we have some announcements to make!
告知！
Announcements!
も、もしや一条莉々華、誕生日記念2025グッズが出るってことー？！
C-Could it be that Ichijou Ririka Birthday Celebration 2025 merch is coming out?!
イエーイ！
Yay!
じゃあこちらをご覧ください！
Please take a look at this!
どん！じゃじゃーん！
Bam! Ta-da!
可愛いー！俺の莉々華ー！
So cute! My Ririka!
チュキチュキチュキ！
Love love love!
チュッティー！はい、こちらね、初めての生誕祭のグッズということで、盛りだくさんなグッズになっております！
Chutty! Yes, as these are her first birthday celebration merch, it's packed full of items!
めっちゃいい！
So awesome!
今回はですね、イラストはトマリ先生に描いていただきました！本当にありがとうございます！
For this time, the illustrations were drawn by Tomari-sensei! Thank you so much!
可愛くて美しくて最高だよね！
It's cute, beautiful, and awesome, right?!
うん！じゃあちょっと詳細も見ていきたいと思います！まずは、こちら！
Yup! Now let's take a closer look at the details. First off, this!
イエーイ！
Yay!
出た出た！みんな画角に入ってね！
There it is! Everyone stay in the frame!
莉々華が大きすぎる！
Ririka is way too huge!
はい、まずはアクリルスマホスタンドです！
Yes, first is the Acrylic Phone Stand!
今回ね、オリジナル衣装で歌って踊ってる莉々華の描き下ろしイラスト！
Featuring a custom illustration of Ririka singing and dancing in her original outfit!
はい、描いてもらいました！でもめちゃくちゃ本当に可愛いし！
Yes, drawn just for this! It's super cute!
もうね、アクリルスマホスタンドなので、スマホを上に置けるということ。つまり、ずっと一緒にいれるということ！イエーイ！
And since it's an acrylic phone stand, you can place your phone on it. Meaning, you can be together forever! Yay!
イエーイ！
Yay!
大事に使ってください！そして、続いてはこちら！
Please use it carefully! And next, we have this!
ジョン！
Ta-da!
可愛いー！
So cute!
ランダムラバーストラップ！
Random Rubber Strap!
やっぱりね、莉々華オタクなので、自分自身も何にしようかなって考えた時に、ラバスト欲しすぎるー！ってなって！
After all, as an otaku myself, when I thought about what to make, I was like "I want rubber straps so badly!"
分かるー！
I get it!
今回ね、上倉エク先生に4種類もの莉々華を描き下ろしていただきました！めっちゃ可愛いー！ありがとうございます！
This time, Kamikura Eku-sensei drew 4 different versions of Ririka for us! They're super cute! Thank you so much!
可愛いー！
So cute!
あ、悪役令嬢なの？
Ah, is that a villainess?
そうだよ！悪役令嬢の莉々華もいます！
Yes! There's even Villainess Ririka!
うわあ！莉々華様！
Whoa! Ririka-sama!
莉々ぃ様だったっけ？
Was it Ririi-sama?
そう、リリィ様！リリィ様ですわ！
Yes, Ririi-sama! It's Ririi-sama, desu wa!
無理しました今！
I forced that one just now!
で、こちらは、えっと、ランダムで1種類封入されております。
And this one will include one random type!
おー！そして、続いてはこちら！
Oooh! And up next, we have this!
ウニのペンケース！
The Uni Pen Case!
可愛い！でしょ！これめちゃめちゃ可愛い！
So cute! Right? It's super cute!
ふわふわでね、もうめちゃくちゃ可愛い！もうお腹裂かれてる？
It's so soft and super cute! Wait, is its stomach split open?
お腹じゃなくて背中！背中！
It's not the stomach, it's the back! The back!
背中は裂けてますが、内臓がペンみたいな感じでね。
Its back is split open, but the pens act like its organs!
なるほどね！可愛いがってあげてください。
I see! Please give it lots of love.
普段使いできるので、ぜひぜひ使ってください！
You can use it every day, so please do!
可愛い！続いてはこちら！
Cute! Up next, we have this!
なんと、限界飯プレートが出ます！
Believe it or not, the Desperate Meal Plate is coming out!
やったー！可愛い！お米だ！
Yay! So cute! It's rice!
そう！これね、お米が敷いてあるようなイラストのプレートなので...
Yeah! The plate has an illustration that looks like rice spread over it...
この上にね、具材を乗せれば、簡単にお手軽に限界飯が作れるという優れものになっております！
So if you put ingredients on top, you can easily make a desperate meal! It's an amazing item!
めっちゃいいじゃん！可愛いね！
That's awesome! It's so cute!
ウニもチラッと書いてある！そう、ウニもいますよ！
Uni is also drawn on it! Yep, Uni is here too!
可愛い！ありがとう！
So cute! Thank you!
じゃあ続いてはこちら！
Now then, up next is this!
まあね、ボイスもやろうかなっていうことで！
Well, I thought I'd do voice packs too!
今回みんな待望のASMRボイス収録しております！やったー！
This time, I recorded the highly-anticipated ASMR voice pack! Yay!
1個目は、「莉々華の部屋で一緒にゲーム」で...
The first one is "Playing Games Together in Ririka's Room"...
莉々華のお家で、隣でなんか一緒にゲームをしてるかのような、ラブラブボイスとなっておりますので...
It's a sweet, loving voice pack where it feels like you're right next to me in my room, playing games together...
よろしくお願いします！
So please check it out!
いいね！買うしかない！
Nice! Gotta buy it!
そしてなんとですね、フルセットの購入特典もございます！こちらです！
And what's more, there's a full set purchase bonus! Here it is!
じゃん！
Ta-da!
はい、まずは直筆サインがついてきます！
Yes, first off, it comes with a handwritten autograph!
で、こちらはですね、もう、莉々華、限定とかじゃなくて...
And for this, it's not limited or anything...
買ってくださった方には全員にお付けしたいと思っているので、ぜひいっぱい購入してもらえると...
I want to give it to everyone who purchases the set, so I'd be super happy if you get lots of them...
嬉しいです！ポストカードに直筆サインをつけてお渡しします！
I'd be so happy! I'll hand them over with a handwritten signature on the postcard!
で、もう1つが、さっき「ASMR 1個目は」って言ったんですけど、2つ目がこちらで...
And the other thing, earlier I said "the first ASMR," but the second one is this...
「あなたの誕生日をお祝い」ということで...
"Celebrating Your Birthday"!
今回ね、今日は莉々華の誕生日をみんなにこうやってお祝いしてもらってるわけですけど...
Today, everyone is celebrating Ririka's birthday like this, but...
莉々華もみんなの誕生日をお祝いしたい！と思って...
Ririka wanted to celebrate all of your birthdays too!
今回準備しました！ぜひ自分の誕生日に聴いてください！
So I prepared this! Please listen to it on your birthday!
はい、じゃあ改めてフルセットはこちらとなります！
Alright, so once again, here is the full set!
じゃん！
Ta-da!
いや、なんて豪華なんだ！あまりにいっぱいありすぎて...
Wow, this is so luxurious! There are so many items...
ねー、もう、絶対に買ってください！絶対に絶対に！よろしくお願いします！
Right? Please, you definitely have to buy it! Absolutely! Thank you so much!
そしてさらに、タレントプレミアムグッズのフルセット特典として...
And furthermore, as a full set bonus for the talent premium goods...
去年から発売されている「hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME」で、なんと使用できるカードが1枚ついてきます！
You get 1 card that can actually be used in the "hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME" released last year!
カードはhololive production OFFICIAL SHOPで購入された方のみが対象となります。
The card is only available for those who purchase from the hololive production OFFICIAL SHOP.
特典につくのは推しをアピールできるキーカード、推しホロメンのカードです。
The bonus card is a key card to show off your fave, a fave holomen card!
カードの詳細や遊び方などについてはホームページにてご確認ください。
Please check the official website for card details and how to play.
なんと！実はまだお知らせがあるんです！
Guess what! There's actually still more news!
こちらをご覧ください！じゃん！
Please look at this! Ta-da!
あー！出たー！よしよしよし！
Ah! There it is! Yes, yes, yes!
一条莉々華のLINEスタンプの制作が決定しましたー！
The production of Ichijou Ririka LINE stamps has been confirmed!
詳細は後日公開となりますので、ご確認のほどよろしくお願いします！
Details will be revealed at a later date, so please stay tuned!
めっちゃ可愛くない？！やばすぎるでしょ！いっぱい使ってください！
Isn't it super cute?! It's so amazing! Please use them a lot!
以上、一条莉々華生誕祭記念ライブのグッズ情報でした！
That was all the merch info for Ichijou Ririka's Birthday Celebration Live!
みんな買っていただけるととっても嬉しいです！
I'd be super happy if everyone gets them!
改めてにはなるんですけど、本当にこうやってね、今回...
Repeating myself a bit, but really, being able to...
生誕ライブ、無事やることができて、もうめちゃくちゃ嬉しい気持ちでいっぱいです！
Hold this birthday live safely like this, I'm just filled with so much happiness!
たくさんの応援コメント、もう常日頃からね、莉々華にいっぱい届いております！
So many supportive comments reach Ririka all the time!
みんなが応援してくれたおかげで、また莉々華、ダンス頑張れた！歌も頑張れた！
Thanks to everyone's support, Ririka was able to work hard on dancing and singing again!
これからもたくさんたくさんみんなといろんな景色見れるように頑張りますので、よろしくお願いします！
I'll keep working hard so we can see many more beautiful views together, so please support me!
でさ... あれ？ReGLOSS...
And, uh... Huh? ReGLOSS...
どこ行った？消えた？！
Where did they go? Did they disappear?!
ええ？！なんで？！どこー？！
Huh?! Why?! Where are you?!
莉々華、こっちだよ！メリーゴーラウンドに乗ってたの？！
Ririka, over here! Were you guys riding the merry-go-round?!
めっちゃ楽しそう！
That looks like so much fun!
白馬の王子様みたいになってるじゃん、番長！
You look like a prince on a white horse, Bancho!
パカラッ パカラッ！いいなー！
Giddy-up, giddy-up! Lucky!
莉々華も乗りたい気持ちはいっぱいあるんだけどさ...
Ririka really wants to ride it too, but...
この後まだアンコールライブもあるから... ごめんね、これ3人用なんだ！
Since we still have the encore live after this... Sorry, this is for 3 people!
こんなに席あったのに、3人用だったの、これ？！
There were so many seats, but it was meant for 3 people?!
4人乗ったら止まっちゃう！重さで？！
If 4 people ride, it'll stop! From the weight?!
莉々華の体重のせいで？！
Because of Ririka's weight?!
まあ、なんか言ってますけれどもね！
Well, they're saying all kinds of things!
この後、莉々華単券のアンコールライブがあります！
After this, there will be Ririka's solo encore live!
アンコールライブでは、ホロライブのあの曲やあの曲を歌っちゃいます！
In the encore live, I'll be singing that hololive song and that song!
思っているので 楽しんでもらえると嬉しいです！
...so I'd be happy if you enjoyed it!
じゃあみんな 今日来てくれて本当ありがとうね！
Everyone, thank you so much for coming today!
この後もゆっくり楽しんでね！
Please keep enjoying the rest of the stream!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
大スキな秘書みならいへ♡
[Message: To my beloved apprentice secretaries♡]
苦手だった歌やダンスをがんばりたい！って
[Message: I used to struggle with singing and dancing,]
思えるようになったのはみんなのおかげだよ。
[Message: but thanks to you all, I now want to do my best at them.]
これからもずっとそばで応援してくれる？
[Message: Will you keep supporting me by my side forever?]
変わらない毎日と新しいチャレンジを一緒に...♡
[Message: Together through everyday life and new challenges...♡]
ホロライブに入れてよかった！！！
[Message: I'm so glad I joined Hololive!!!]